===============OP=================
===============ED=================
今はまだ明日がある
For now, there is still a tomorrow.
ルルーシュ·ランペルージには夢を見るべき明日がある
For Lelouch Lamperouge,
there is still a tomorrow he can dream of.
そのよりどころこそ謎の少女C.C.から手に入れた
A dream based on the Geass
he alone possesses...
which was given to him
by the mysterious girl C.C.
彼だけのギアス
いかなる相手にでも命令を下せる絶対遵守の力
The absolute power to
compel anyone to obey him.
ギアスを使い　ルルーシュは神聖ブリタニア帝国の破壊を決意する
Using his Geass, Lelouch is determined
to destroy the Holy Britannian Empire.
すべては母の敵を討ち
All to avenge the death of his mother...
妹ナナリーが幸せに過ごせる世界をつくるために
and to create a world in which his
younger sister Nunnally can live happily.
植民地エリア11となった日本は
From Japan, now the colony called Area 11,
a vow to the world begins to be realized.
今　世界に向けた　誓いが始まる
朝も夜も恋い焦がれて
Asa mo yoru mo koikogarete
Morning and night, I long for you
星になるよ 君守る
hoshi ni naru yo kimi mamoru
I'll become a star and protect you
戦いは行方知らず
tatakai wa yukue shirazu
No matter where the battle may take me
明日と昨日の交差点で
ashita to kinou no kousaten de
At the intersection of tomorrow and yesterday
交わらない君と僕
majiwaranai kimi to boku
You and I can't be together
今行くよ 僕は流れ星
ima iku yo boku wa nagareboshi
I'm a shooting star, on my way right now
世界が朽ち果てても 変わることの無いものがある
sekai ga kuchihatetemo
Even if the world crumbles apart
kawaru koto no nai mono ga aru
There are things which will never change
涙を堪えてでも 守るべきものが僕らにはある
namida wo koraete demo
Even as we bear tears in our eyes
mamorubeki mono ga bokura ni wa aru
There are things we must protect
（nononono）
nanman'nen nan'okunen mae kara no
A message that's been in my body
遅れまいと メッセージが絶えない
（no）
message ga tainai de
For thousands and millions of years,
剥き出す 撃ち抜く
uzukidasu... mayoi wa nai
Springs out... I have no reservations
（迷いは無い）
narihibiku... kantan da
Roars out... It's easy
（簡単だ）
しゃがれた声で 傷だらけの手で 君守る
shagareta koe de... asu wo yobu
In a hoarse voice... Calling tomorrow
kizudarake no te de... kimi mamoru
With my wounded hands... I protect you
way got you could like
I continue to fight...
I continue to fight!
朝も夜も恋い焦がれて
asa mo yoru mo koikogarete
Morning and night, I long for you
星になるよ 君守る
hoshi ni naru yo kimi mamoru
I'll become a star and protect you
戦いは行方知らず
tatakai wa yukue shirazu
No matter where the battle may take me
明日と昨日の交差点で
ashita to kinou no kousaten de
At the intersection of tomorrow and yesterday
交わらない君と僕
majiwaranai kimi to boku
You and I can't be together
宿命を切り裂く流れ星
sadame wo kirisaku nagareboshi
I'm a shooting star, tearing fate apart
溢れる君の涙 僕が今奪い去る
afureru kimi no namida boku ga ima ubaisaru
I'll take away your overflowing tears right now
COUNTERATTACK AT THE GALLOWS
うん？
子供
A child?
はい　殺した人の数は覚えていません
That's right, I can't remember
how many people I've killed.
歯を磨いたり　食事をしたことを数える人はいません　同じことです
Nobody counts the number of times
they brush their teeth or eat meals.
Same with this.
僕のギアスは暗殺に向いている
My Geass is suited to assassination.
そう言われました
That's what I was told. And so I killed.
だから殺してきた
ほかにいる所もなかったし
There was no other place where I could live.
潜入工作　弟役ですか
An infiltration operation?
And I'd be playing a little brother?
僕にやれるでしょうか
Are you sure I can pull this off?
僕は親も家族も知りませんから
I've never known any parents or family, so...
いえ　それが命令なら
No. If that's your order...
僕の兄は　ルルーシュ·ランペルージ
then my big brother shall be Lelouch Lamperouge.
お前のギアスは時を止める能力か
Your Geass is the power to stop time?!
答える理由はありません
I have no reason to answer you.
僕に与えられた指令は
The orders given to me are as follows:
ルルーシュ·ランペルージの記憶が戻ったなら
If Lelouch Lamperouge's memories return...
ゼロが復活したなら
If Zero is reborn, then he is to die.
抹殺する
Sixteen...
17 18
Seventeen... Eighteen... Nineteen...
なんです　その数字は
What's that you're counting?
お前が現れたときから
Since you appeared, I've been
counting the seconds to myself.
オレは心の中で時を数えていた
だが　今はその数値がずれている
But now the count is out of synch.
なぜだと思う
Now, why do you think that is?
ナナリーを捜すための駒になってもらう
I'll make you my pawn to find Nunnally.
ロロ　お前が止めたのは時間ではない
Rolo, it isn't time that you're stopping.
オレの体感時間だけだ
It's just my physical sensation of time.
それが分かったところで僕には勝てません
Even if you understand that, you can't beat me.
そう　誰も僕と同じ時間は　生きられない
That's right... Nobody can live
in the same time with me.
ロロ　お前は正しい
Rolo, you're correct.
すぐにオレを殺さないのは　分かっているからだろう
You can't kill me right away
because you know that, can you?
このままでは　2つとも手に入らないと
As things stand,
you won't gain either of two things.
2つ？
Two things?
1つは　このオレを餌に捜していたC.C.
First, you won't get C.C., for which
I've been the bait in your search.
オレを見逃してくれたら
If you let me go, I'll draw out C.C. for you.
C.C.を　引きずり出してやろう
売るのか　C.C.を
You'd sell out C.C.?
自分の命とは　比べられないからな
She isn't worth my own life.
もう1つは
And the other thing?
お前の命
Your life.
ふっ　命なんて
Like I care about that.
ロロ　未来とはなんだ
Rolo, what is the future?
未来とは希望だ
The future is hope!
お前の任務の先に　希望はあるのか
Do you have any hope beyond your mission?
C.C.を捕まえることで
If you capture C.C., what sort
of future will it open for you?
お前にはどんな未来が開ける
今のままだ　何も変わらない
Things will just go on as they
are and nothing will change!
これは任務だ
This is my mission!
オレを殺したら　任務は果たせない
Kill me and your mission will never be complete!
C.C.を捕まえたいんだろう
You want to capture C.C., don't you?!
明日　オレがC.C.を引きずり出してやろう
Tomorrow, I'll lure C.C. out.
それでお前は新しい未来をつかめる
Once I do, a new future will be in your grasp!
大丈夫　うそはつかないよ
Don't worry. I wouldn't lie to you.
お前にだけは…
Never to you.
アオモリを思い出すわね
This reminds me of Aomori.
あれよりはましだろ
This is better than that was. At least
everyone here is wearing their clothes.
全員　服を着ているからな
総領事にはゼロがギアスをかけたんでしょ
Zero used his Geass on the consul
general, right? So, why is he doing this?
なのに　どうして
さぁな
Who knows? Still, if they take this place
away from us, then we and Lelouch will be...
ただ　ここを取られると　私たちとルルーシュは…
また　バラバラに
...split up again.
意外だな
How unexpected. You came alone.
一人で来るとは
中華連邦の総領事は　合衆国日本を承認したはずだけど
I thought the Chinese Federation consul general
had recognized the United States of Japan.
その方は　亡くなられる予定だ
The plan is for him to be killed.
それとも　ここで黒の騎士団がついえる道を選ぶか？
Or do the Black Knights choose
the path of destruction right here?
待て　いきなりそんな
Hold it! You can't just spring that on us...
分かった
I see. You can just arrange it so that
the consul general is killed fighting us.
総領事は私たちと戦って死んだことにすればいい
C.C.
C.C.?!
ゼロは思わぬ引き金を　引いたらしいな
It seems Zero has pulled a
trigger he wasn't planning to.
高邁なる野望か　俗なる野心か
Will this be noble ambition or base treachery?
とりあえず　ロロが待つだけの時間は稼いだ
Anyway, Rolo waiting for me
has bought me some time.
C.C.が手に入るとなれば
If he gets C.C., he'll most likely
overlook my regaining my memories.
オレの記憶のことは見過ごしてくれるだろう
だが　あいつの根源はなんだ
Still, what is his motivation?
ブリタニアでの出世や忠誠とは違うようだが
It doesn't seem to be a desire for
promotion in Britannia or loyalty.
とすると
Or is there another line
of inquiry I should follow?
もう一つのラインを探るべきか
危険なカードだが　その分価値はある
That's a dangerous card,
but it has its merits.
躊躇する余裕はない
I don't have any time to hesitate.
明日には藤堂たちが処刑されてしまうのだから
Because tomorrow, Tohdoh and the
others are going to be executed!
どうする
What should I do?
Rolo knows about my Geass now.
オレのギアスはロロにばれている
なんとかロロを殺せたとしても
Even if I managed to kill him somehow, the O.S.I.
would know that I've regained my memories!
オレの記憶が戻ったと機情に知られてしまう
そうなれば　ナナリーが…
And if that happens,
then Nunnally will be!
ナナリーを救い出すまでは　学生の振りを続けるしかないか
I guess I'll have to keep playing student
until Nunnally has been rescued.
幸い
Fortunately, it looks like there's barely any
relationship between Guilford's men and the O.S.I.
ギルフォードたちと機情のつながりは薄いようだ
隠してあるナイトメアが発見されていないことからも　それは分かる
The fact that they haven't found
the Knightmare I hid tells me that.
だが　それだけだ
But that's all I have in my favor.
What should I do?
どうすればいい
黒の騎士団を救い出し
How do I save the Black Knights and
take care of Rolo at the same time?
同時にロロを排除する方法は
納得できません
I can't accept that!
ブルーノを殺したのはあのガキじゃないんですか
You're telling me you're going to
overlook that he killed Bruno?!
これで　5人目です
That's the fifth one!
ビクトルなんて　ヤツのロケットに触っただけで
All Victor did was touch
the kid's locket, and then!
彼はふだんから問題があった
Victor had his own personality problems.
殺されるほどではないでしょう
That didn't mean he had to be killed!
ゼロを名乗る者が現れた以上
Now that we've got this guy claiming to be Zero,
we have to get our priorities straight!
我々はよりまとまらねば
仲間を殺すような死神とチームは組めません
I can't be a teammate with a
guy who kills his own people!
チーム？大事なのは任務でしょ
Team? The mission is what's important, isn't it?
仲間なんて
Who cares about teammates?
なあ　復活したゼロって　あのゼロかな
Hey, is this new Zero the same as our Zero?
さあな
I dunno.
どちらにしろ　また見捨てるつもりだろ　私たちを
Either way, we're probably
going to be abandoned again.
総領事館の爆発事故原因は
What was the source of the
explosions in the consulate?
いまだ　公式発表は
They still haven't issued a formal statement.
刑の執行は認めるとの連絡があっただけです
All they've said is that they acknowledge
the punishment to be carried out.
処刑など　ただの見せしめ
An execution is just a warning to others.
我ながら　品のない手段だ
This is so unrefined of us.
現れるでしょうか　ゼロは
You think Zero will show himself?
出てこなければ　それでいい
Even if he doesn't, it'll still be all right.
奇跡を起こそうとしないゼロならば
A Zero who can't pull off a miracle
won't gain the support of the people.
民衆の支持は得られない
そこまで　お考えでしたか
You've thought it that far through, sir?
しかし　私は現れてほしいと
However, I want him to show up.
いや　願っているのだ
Or rather, I pray that he does.
いずこかにおられる　我が姫様のために
For the sake of Her Highness,
wherever she is now.
なぜ合衆国日本をお認めになったのですか
Why did you recognize the U.S.J.?
朱禁城に確認もせず　独断で
On your own, without confirmation
from the Vermilion Forbidden City.
いかに大宦官の1人とはいえ
Even if you are one of the High
Eunuchs, that was unforgivable!
許されることではありません
ゼロを利用するにせよ
Just what were you planning to use Zero for?!
いかなる目算があって
ゼロを利用するなどあってはならぬ
We mustn't use Zero for anything!
Zero must be pleased!
ゼロこそが　幸せ
天子様の御意向は
And what are the Empress's feelings on this?
あんな小娘よりゼロよ
Zero is more important than that little brat!
ゼロこそ私を幸せにしてくれるということが絶対の法則
The absolute law I must follow is
that Zero shall bring me happiness!
この売国奴が
You damned traitor!
紅天　すでに死す
The Vermilion Dynasty is dead already.
ダメだ
It's no use! Killing him, controlling
the information, disguising it...
殺しも　情報操作も　偽装も
どこをたどっても　ロロがネックになる
No matter what I try,
Rolo remains an obstacle!
くっ…　処刑が始まる前に　なんとか
I have to find what's behind the information
I have before the execution starts!
あの情報の裏付けを…
かつて　黒の騎士団を名乗り
It seems that the execution
of the rebel terrorists...
エリア11を混乱させた　テロリストの処刑が
who formerly called themselves the
Black Knights will be starting soon.
今　正に行われようとしています
部下の処刑に果たしてゼロは姿を現すのでしょうか
Will Zero appear to stop the
execution of his followers?
ゼロ様　どうか…
Oh Zero, please!
藤堂将軍
General Tohdoh!
殺さないで
Don't kill them!
どうして？
ゼロは我々を裏切ったのだ
Zero betrayed us.
I doubt he'll come to save us now!
助けに来るはずがない
ぜってぇ～来る　あいつが本物なら
He's gonna come!
If he's the real one, if he's alive,
then he'll make a miracle happen!
生きていたなら　奇跡を起こしにやってくるんだ
奇跡…か
A miracle, huh?
警戒を怠るな
Maintain tight surveillance!
可能性は低いが
It's a long shot, but it's possible C.C. may show up.
C.C.の出現はありうる
扇要
Kaname Ohgi... This is the end.
これで　終わりになる
出てこい　ぜろ
Show yourself, Zero!
義父上　アンドレアス·ダールトンの敵…
My father, Andreas Darlton, shall be avenged!
本隊から　極秘命令です
I have top secret orders from headquarters.
通信の傍受を避けるため
Communications are being monitored,
so I'm to deliver them to you verbally.
口頭伝達せよとのことですが
あなたの存在をお借りしますよ
I'll be filling in for you.
これは　どう受け取ったら　いいのかしら
So, just how are we supposed to interpret this?
ゼロが現れたら　動いてくれていい
If Zero appears, you can act as you wish.
我々なら　たとえブリタニアに発砲しても　知らん顔を決め込めると
So, even if we start shooting at the Britannians,
you can pretend you know nothing about it.
悪い取引ではないはずだ
I don't think it's such a bad deal.
武官と聞いていたが
You may be a military officer, but
you can play politics as well, I see.
政治もできるようだな
キンメル卿　先行量産機に問題はないか
Sir Kimmel, any problems with
that A.S.E.E.C. mass-pro unit?
機情が使ったからな
It may have some peculiarities left
from when the O.S.I. were using it.
変な癖が残っているかもしれん
大事な機体だ
It's a valuable machine. Report
in if it acts up in any way.
少しでも調子が悪ければ　報告してくれ
こちらキンメル
This is Kimmel.
ヴィンセントに異常なし
No problems with Vincent. Moving out.
いけます
ルルーシュ　約束を果たさなければ
Lelouch, if you don't keep your promise, you'll die.
殺すだけ
キルフォード卿
Lord Guilford.
さあ　いよいよ　刑の執行時間です
It's almost time for the execution!
黒の騎士団の残党に　正義の裁きが下されます
The remnants of the Black Knights
shall feel the judgment of justice!
ゼロ様
Zero!
お願いです
Please!
どうか　奇跡を
Make a miracle!
イレヴンたちよ
Elevens!
お前たちが　信じたゼロは現れなかった
The Zero which you believed in hasn't shown up!
すべてはまやかし
It's all been a deception!
ヤツは私の求める正々堂々の勝負から逃げたのだ
He has fled from a fair and honest
duel which I requested. Take aim!
構え
嫌だ
No, please!
みんな
Guys...
動くな
Don't move! If you go out
now, you'll just die with them!
ここから出たら　お前も殺される
分かってる　でも…
I know, but!
もういい
Let it end. We've all done a fine job.
よくやったよ　オレたち
違うな
You're wrong!
間違ってるぞ　ギルフォード
You're wrong, Guilford!
来てくれた　でも…
He came! But!
私たちも手が出せない
We can't do anything. What
can he do, all by himself?!
どうする　たった一人で
なるほど　後ろに回ったか
I see... You snuck up behind me, Zero!
ゼロ
ギルフォードよ
Guilford! Those aren't terrorists you're executing!
貴公が処刑しようとしているのはテロリストではない
我が合衆国軍　黒の騎士団の兵士だ
They are the Black Knights! Soldiers of
the army of the United States of Japan!
国際法にのっとり
You expect me to recognize them as
prisoners under International Law?
捕虜として認めよと
ゼロ
Zero!
出てきたね　やっぱり
So, you did come, as I expected.
でも　僕との約束を破ったら　死んでもらうよ
But if you break your promise
to me, I'll kill you, Zero.
ゼロ　いや…
Or rather, you, Lelouch Lamperouge!
ルルーシュ·ランペルージ
ゼロです　ゼロが現れました
It's Zero! Zero has appeared!
What a foolish action on his part!
なんという　愚かな行為でしょう
ゼロが？
Zero!
どうして…
Why?
本物なのか？
Is it the real one?
決まってんだろ！ゼロ！
Of course he is! ZERO-O-O!
そういや　処刑の発表はあったけど　それ以上の報道は…
Come to think of it, there was that
announcement of his execution, but...
We've heard nothing more on the news.
いや　でも…
No, but!
一人です　ゼロは一人です
He's alone! Zero is all alone!
ナイトメア·フレームに乗っているということは　自首が目的ではないのでしょう
As he is riding atop a Knightmare Frame,
it's clear that he's not here to surrender.
しかし　一人で戦うつもりなら…
However, if he intends to fight alone...
ほら　私の言ったとおりでしょう？
See? Just like I said he would!
なら　去年の計画どおりに事を進めましょう
Then let's continue the operation from last year.
ゼロがこのピンチをくぐり抜けられたらだけどね
Assuming Zero can wriggle out
of this little pinch.
咲世子
Sayoko, I'd like you to make
preparations for that contingency plan.
先々のために　例の手配準備に入ってほしい
ブリタニア軍側は…
The Britannian soldiers seem
to be waiting for Zero's move.
ルルーシュ？
Where's Lelouch?
ロロが付いています
Rolo's with him. They've been at the
Spiral Theater for the last 30 minutes.
30分前からスパイラルシアターに
We've yet to see a major move. The tense
atmosphere at the execution site continues to flow.
お久しぶりです　ギルフォード卿
It's been quite a while, Lord Guilford.
出てきて　昔話でもいかがですか？
Why don't you come out and we
can talk about the good old days?
せっかくのお誘いだが　遠慮しておこう
Tempting as that invitation is,
I'll stay where I am.
過去の因縁にはナイトメアでお応えしたいが
Why don't we settle our past
grudges inside our Knightmares?
外に出てこないんじゃギアスが使えない
Unless Guilford comes out,
he can't use his Geass!
ふん　君らしいな
Hmpf! How typical of you!
Then let's set some rules!
では　ルールを決めよう
ルール？
Rules?
決闘のルールだよ
The rules of our duel.
決着は1対1で　つけるべきだ
We'll settle this one-on-one!
いいだろう　ほかの者には　手を出させない
Very well. No one else will interfere with this.
武器は1つだけ
We will each have only one weapon.
よかろう
Agreed!
私の武器はこれだ
I choose this as my weapon!
では　私はその盾を貸してもらおう
Then I shall borrow that shield as mine.
何？それは…
What? But, that's...
これでいい
It will do.
暴徒鎮圧用のシールドじゃあ…
A riot shield?
Did he plan from the start...
まさか　最初っから…
自決する気か
...to kill himself?
失望だな　ゼロ
You disappoint me, Zero.
どうしますか？
What shall we do?
寄生虫たる大宦官　その一人を始末できた借りがある
I owe him a debt for giving me a way to
deal with that parasite of a high eunuch.
しかし　これは永続調和に基づく契りではない
However, this isn't a pledge
based on Permanent Harmony.
ゼロが無能ならば
黒の騎士団は外交の道具となってもらうしかないだろう
If Zero turns out to be incompetent, then we'll just
use the Black Knights as our diplomatic tools.
質問しよう　ギルフォード卿
I have a question for you, Lord Guilford.
正義で倒せない悪がいるとき　君はどうする？
What do you do when there is an
evil you cannot defeat by justice?
悪に手を染めてでも　悪を倒すか
Do you stain your hands with
evil so as to destroy evil?
それとも己が正義を貫き悪に屈するをよしとするか
Or do you uphold your justice
even if you must surrender to evil?
いずれにせよ　悪は残る
In either case, evil remains.
矛盾　言葉遊びか…
A contradiction... Is it a word play?
我が正義は　姫様の下に
Justice is whatever my princess says it is!
なるほど　私なら　悪をなして　巨悪を討つ!
I see! In my case...
I commit evil in order to destroy the greater evil!
イエス　ユア　ハイネス
Yes, Your Highness.
これは！？
What the?!
じ…地震！？
E- Earthquake?!
いや　この作戦は…
No! This strategy is!
ブラックリベリオンのときの！？
The one from the Black Rebellion?!
第12歩兵部隊　レベル4の階層コントロールルームに向かえ
Infantry unit 12!
Head for the control room on level 4!
One of Zero's men is in there!
ゼロの部下が…
カレン突入指揮を執れ
Kallen! Charge in and take command!
はい
Roger! Autonomous armored
combat machine unit, follow me!
自在戦闘装甲機部隊はついてこい
扇さんたちの救出が　最優先だ
Saving Ohgi and the others has top priority!
アルファ4より　アルファ1　応答願います
Alpha 4 to alpha 1! Please respond!
Alpha 1! Alpha 1! Shit! Somebody, answer me!
アルファ1　アルファ1！
くそ　誰か…
ひきょうな
You dishonorable!
何が1対1か
One-on-one my ass!
な　何っ！？
Wha?!
バート
Bart!
黒の騎士団よ　敵は我が領内に落ちた
Black Knights!
The enemies have fallen into our territory!
ブリタニア軍を壊滅し同胞を救い出せ
Wipe out the Britannian forces
and save your comrades!
同胞…
Comrades...
租界の構造を逆手に取ったか
He used the structure of the
settlement against them?!
急げ　ブリタニアが体勢を整える前に全員解放するんだ
Hurry up! Release everyone before
the Britannian forces can regroup!
逃げられてしまう　中華連邦内に…
They're going to escape!
Right into the Chinese Federation!
我々の目的はあくまでC.C.だ
C.C. remains our primary target!
Leave this to Guilford!
そちらは　ギルフォードに任せておけ
テロリストが
Damned terrorists!
ブリタニア　ここはね　もう日本の領土なんだよ
Britannia!
This is Japanese territory now!
日本など　存在しない
Japan doesn't exist!
あっそ…
Oh, really?
This is why I hate Britannia!
これだから　ブリタニアは…
さらばだ　イレヴンのエース
Goodbye, Eleven ace!
防いだ…この距離で
Blocked! At this range?!
これが輻射波動　懐に入ったときに　私の勝ちは決まっていたの
This is the radiant wave surger!
The moment you came in close,
my victory was assured!
じゃあね
So long.
よくも　アルフレッドを…
Alfred! How dare you!
撃つな　ここは中華連邦の治外法権区だぞ
Don't shoot!
This is Chinese Federation territory!
しかし…
But!
報道カメラも入ってるんだ
There are broadcast cameras here, too!
ヴィ…ヴィンセントが
Th- The Vincent!
ヴィンセントが突入しました
The Vincent's charged inside!
こっちは動けない　逃げて
I can't move from here!
Run for it!
来たか…
You've come...
You've finally come, Rolo!
来てしまったのか？ロロ
やっぱり逃げるんですね？
So, you are running.
So much for your promise to give me C.C....
C.C.を差し出す約束は？
ルルーシュ　最初から僕にうそを…
Lelouch...
You were lying to me from the start!
まだ…　まだ捕まるわけには…
Not yet!
I can't be caught yet!
僕に未来をくれると言ったくせに…
All that talk about
giving me a future!
ここで　死ぬわけには…
I can't die here!
任務さえ果たせば　未来はつながるんだ
If I just complete my mission,
I'll open the way to my future!
しまった…
Oh, crap!
物理現象は止められない
I can't stop a physical object!
直撃コースだ　こんな所で…
It'll be a direct hit!
There's no way I can dodge it!
やめろ　デヴィッド
David, stop! If you hit the Chinese
Federation consulate, it'll be an act of war!
総領事館にあたったら　中華連邦との戦争になるぞ
分かってる
I know that.
な…なぜ…
Wh-Why?
どうして　僕を…
Why did you save me?
お前が　弟だから…
Because... you're my little brother.
植え付けられた記憶だったとしても　お前と過ごしたあの時間に　うそはなかった
The memories may have been planted in me,
but the time we spent together was real!
今までのことが　うそじゃなかったって…
You're saying...
All the things we did till now weren't a lie?
お前が弟だから…
Because you're my little brother!
弟？僕が…
Brother...
Me?
あの日　誕生日がなかった僕に　初めて…それも？
That day... After never having a
birthday ever, for the first time, I!
So, that's why?
自分の命が大事だってそう言ったくせに
What about when you said
your life was more important?
そんな　くだらない理由で…
For such a stupid reason, you'd?!
約束したからな　お前の新しい未来
I made a promise to you.
For your new future.
お前の未来は　オレと…
Your future... with me.
ゼロ　ここで因縁を断とう
Zero! We'll settle things now!
私の一撃で
With one blow from me!
この鉄槌で
With this iron hammer!
何！？
What?! Sir Kimmel,
what's the meaning of this?!
どういうつもりか？キンメル卿
あっ　いや　これは…
Uh, no! I just!
まさか　ゼロの仲間か！？
Are you one of Zero's men?!
ちがう…僕は　ルルーシュが死ぬと　任務が…
No, I... If Lelouch dies,
then my mission is!
いや　でも…
No, but...
What am I doing?!
何をしているんだ　僕は
はい
Yes?
ロロ　まずい　ヴィレッタ先生からだ
Rolo? Trouble. It's Coach Villetta.
IMオープンでつなぐぞ
（IM ：Instant Messenger）
I'll connect you on the open I.M.
ロロか？どこに行っていた？
Rolo? Where did you go?
その…
Well...
やだな　先生
Coach, c'mon!
Can't we even go to the toilet in peace?
トイレぐらい別々にさせてくださいよ
で　なんでしたっけ？さっきの…
So, what were you calling about?
総領事館の話だろ？
About the consulate, of course.
ああ～　すごい騒ぎらしいですね
Oh, yeah. Looks like a real mess down there.
いけない　今までのことが知られたら…
Uh-oh! If they find out what's happened,
I'll be thrown out of the O.S. I!
機情から排除される
あの人だって…
Even that person would!
分かっていますよ
I understand. I'll keep my little
brother out of danger from now on.
もう　危ないことに　弟を巻き込みません
当たり前じゃないですか
Of course not! People being killed is
no world for Rolo to be involved in.
ロロには　人殺しがある世界なんて似合わない
そこまでだ　ブリタニアの諸君
That's enough, Britannians!
これ以上は武力介入とみなす
Any further action will be taken as
armed intervention. Withdraw at once!
引き揚げたまえ
HEY!!!
よかったぁ…
Thank goodness!
扇さん
Ohgi!
扇…
ありがとう　カレン
Thanks, Kallen.
ううん　藤堂さんたちも…よかった
Uh-uh!
And Tohdoh and the others...
Thank goodness!
すまない　迷惑を掛けた
Sorry for being such trouble.
苦労したんでしょ？
Must have been hard for you.
そっちだって…
And for you!
なあ　あのナイトメアは？
Hey, who's in that Knightmare?
さあ
I dunno. It was an enemy unit, but
I don't know who's piloting it now.
あの機体は　敵だったんだけど
今のパイロットは　私も…
ゼロを守ったんだ
They protected Zero. At the very
least, they're not an enemy.
少なくとも　敵ではないだろう
C.C.がいるのに　僕は　もう…
C.C.'s right here, but now I!
最初から　ブリタニアには　安らぎはなかったんだ
From the beginning,
you never felt at ease with Britannia.
お前の居場所は　ここにある
Here is where you belong.
Heh... Now he's mine.
ふ　落ちたな
こんな資料を司令室に残しているぐらいだ
Convenient, his leaving this
data in the control room.
ギアスしか取り柄がないのだろう
I think the only value
he has is for his Geass.
こいつのパスワードが役に立つとはな
The password in this came in handy.
それに…
As well as...
パターン　デルタ
Pattern Delta.
そうだ
Correct. When Zero's unit takes that course,
shoot the pursuing Knightmare from behind.
ゼロの機体がその軌道を取ったとき
追っているナイトメアを背後から撃て
その後　ゼロが脱出したなら　相手のナイトメアを完全に破壊しろ
After that, if Zero escapes,
destroy the opposing Knightmare completely.
脱出しない場合は　その場で待機
If he does not escape,
stand by where you are.
ああ…よく分かった
Sure. I understand perfectly.
ナナリーがいるべき所を　奪い取った偽者め
You damned little phony,
trying to take Nunnally's place!
さんざん　使い倒して　ボロぞうきんのように　捨ててやる
I'll use you up and then throw you
away like a ragged dust cloth!
胸の中 いつか拾った
Mune no naka itsuka hirotta
Someday let's try to pick up and rebuild
幸せの欠片 集めてみよう
Shiawase no kakera atsumete miyou
The fragments of happiness in our hearts
忘れかけていたメロディー
Wasurekaketeita melody
That nearly forgotten melody
色褪せず僕の真ん中に
Iroasezu boku no man'naka ni
Stay vivid, deep inside of me
ありがとう 心から 僕に今があるのはみんなのおかげさ
Arigatou kokoro kara
I thank you from the bottom of my heart
Boku ni ima ga aru no wa minna no okagesa
Everything I have now, I owe to everyone
ありがとう 心から 次は僕がみんなにハッピー贈るよ
Arigatou kokoro kara
I thank you from the bottom of my heart
Tsugi wa boku ga minna ni happy okuru yo
Next I'll send happiness to everyone
何もかも忘れないよ あの日の僕も僕だから
Nanimokamo wasurenai yo
I won't forget anything
Ano hi no boku mo boku dakara
Because I'm still the same as I was that day
「大好きだよ」って　いつも言ってあげなきゃ駄目だね
Daisuki da yo'tte itsumo
You need me to keep on saying
Itte agenakya dame da ne
How much I love you
涙がこぼれそうな長い夜は ふっと振り返って
Namida ga kobore sou na nagai yoru wa
On those long nights, your tears about to overflow
Futto furikaette
Just turn around
足跡を辿るんだ あの日を忘れないように
Ashiato wo tadorun'da
Follow those footprints
Ano hi wo wasurenai you ni
So that you'll never forget that day
何が　ロロ·ランペルージだ
あんなヤツを弟と思っていたなんて
Who does Rolo Lamperouge think he is?
Thinking he was my little brother...
身震いするほどの屈辱だ
I practically shudder from the disgrace!
しかし　お前が便利な駒になるのなら…
It's a shame, but if he'd remained
loyal to his duty to the O.S.I.,
だが　忘れるな
お前は　ナナリーの偽者でしか…
he would have been killed right
then and there and I'd be rid of him.
Still, you'll make a convenient pawn,
so I'll let you remain at my side.
Still, never forget!
All you are is a fake Nunnally!
Until the day I can use you
best on the chessboard comes,
I'll keep playing this game of
being your brother for now.
KNIGHTS OF THE ROUND